const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="civiledu",a=200,t=120,i=[{id:86,question:"Which of the following bodies is responsible for defending the country against external aggression? The",option:{a:"Army",b:"Civil defense.",c:"Customs.",d:"Police."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:377,question:"Which of the following is not a way of improving public service?",option:{a:"Politicization",b:"Refresher courses",c:"The use of Code Conduct Bureau",d:"Reformation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:202,question:"Cultism can lead to",option:{a:"Immoral activities and indiscipline",b:"Maintenance of law and order in the society",c:"Corrupt free society",d:"Sound cultural development"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:139,question:"One of the following is not a federal road agencies",option:{a:"DTO",b:"FRSC",c:"TRACE",d:"VIO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:128,question:"One of the following is not a pressure group",option:{a:"National Association of Nigeria Student (NANS)",b:"Nigeria Labour Congress (NLC)",c:"Academic Staff Union of Universities (ASUU)",d:"Committee for Defense of Human Right (CDHR)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:316,question:"Which of the following is the cleanest source of water in Nigeria",option:{a:"pond water",b:"river water",c:"rain water",d:"lagoon water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:312,question:"In Lagos state and some other states in Nigeria, motorcycle (okada) riders are expected to wear ............ while on motion",option:{a:"Boot",b:"Hand glove",c:"Crash helmet",d:"Black coloured shirt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:307,question:"Civic Education is also known as ....................",option:{a:"Organizational Structure",b:"Citizenship Education",c:"Customers Opinion",d:"Government Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:244,question:"The president belongs to .......... arm of the government",option:{a:"Legislative",b:"Judiciary",c:"Executive",d:"Anti-crime"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:427,question:"Which of the following function is not performed by the Public Service Commission?",option:{a:"Evaluating the performance of ministries and departments",b:"Advising government on technical matters",c:"Preparing the annual budget and assenting to it",d:"Organizing enlightenment program and training"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:218,question:"Which one of the following is the founding father of Nigeria nationalism?",option:{a:"Goodluck Jonathan",b:"Oba Kosoko",c:"Herbert Macaulay",d:"Olusegun Obasanjo"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:382,question:"The most important contribution of responsible parenthood to national development is that it",option:{a:"increases youthful population",b:"fosters national integration",c:"augments the nation workforce",d:"breeds dependable citizenry"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:81,question:"The United Nations universal declaration on human rights was proposed in the year",option:{a:"1925",b:"1930",c:"1946",d:"1948"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:311,question:"Another word for abduction is ...........................",option:{a:"to steal",b:"to adopt",c:"to kidnap",d:"to kill"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:29,question:"The implication of positive communal relationships is that it",option:{a:"promotes solidarity and love",b:"ensures obedience to constituted authority",c:"encourages ethnic diversity",d:"promotes rural-urban drift."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:206,question:"The process of enlightening or training citizens on their rights and responsibilities is known as",option:{a:"Workshop training",b:"Citizenship Education",c:"Political Education",d:"Citizenship Rights"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:415,question:"A very important segment of the society which is distinct from government, business and home is the",option:{a:"civil society",b:"public service",c:"mass media",d:"traditional institution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:360,question:"The general attitude of government and society towards cultism is that of",option:{a:"affection",b:"sympathy",c:"abhorrence",d:"support"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:122,question:"........... is the verdict that results when a law court declares a defendant guilty of a crime",option:{a:"immunity clause",b:"conviction",c:"customary clause",d:"traditions"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:16,question:"The division of Nigeria into various constituencies with each electing a person to represent it in the National Assembly is a demonstration of",option:{a:"checks and balances",b:"popular participation",c:"political rivalry among the constituents",d:"drive towards secession in the country."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:403,question:"Law and order can best be maintained in Nigeria through the",option:{a:"prohibition of public protest",b:"enforcement of rules and regulations",c:"use of divide and rule policy",d:"promotion of indigenization policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:105,question:"Newspapers and magazine and example of ..... media",option:{a:"print",b:"electronic",c:"advertising",d:"mass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:375,question:"Which of the following is not an example of civil society group?",option:{a:"United Action for Democracy",b:"United Nations Organization",c:"Transition Monitoring Group",d:"Amnesty International"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:292,question:"Free, fair and credible elections are attributes of .......",option:{a:"undemocratic government",b:"democratic government",c:"military regime",d:"monarchical governance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:226,question:"The process of learning the political attitudes, values and beliefs that are relevant to the political system is known as",option:{a:"political culture",b:"political socialization",c:"political participation",d:"political science"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:431,question:"Justice demands that people should always do what is",option:{a:"persistently convenient",b:"consistently right",c:"individually acceptable",d:"courageously necessary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:118,question:"The following factors are responsible for drug abuse except",option:{a:"family upbringing",b:"high stress level",c:"poverty",d:"foster parenthood"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:267,question:"The right practice of democracy can",option:{a:"ensure equity, justice and far play",b:"discourage political education and awareness’",c:"political unrest",d:"lawlessness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:210,question:"For which of these can someone be arrested while driving on a high way",option:{a:"driving and laughing",b:"driving and singing",c:"driving and eating or receiving phone call",d:"driving and crying"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:125,question:"The following are causes of emergency rule except",option:{a:"crisis",b:"blood lettings",c:"stage peaceful protest",d:"sabotage / terrorism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:238,question:"The rule of law simply means",option:{a:"The ruling of a lawful leader",b:"The absence of political instability",c:"Supremacy of the law",d:"The ruling of legislators"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:424,question:"The foreign policy objective of Nigeria as enshrined in the 1999 Constitution exclude the promotion of",option:{a:"national interest",b:"African integration",c:"support for donor agencies",d:"just world economic order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:138,question:"Traffic lights are also known and referred to as",option:{a:"three directives light",b:"spotlight",c:"flow traffic directive",d:"informative sign"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:88,question:"In a parliamentary system of government, the powers of the executive is vested in the office of the",option:{a:"minister.",b:"premier",c:"president.",d:"prime minister."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:41,question:"One of the major barriers to national development is the",option:{a:"low poverty level",b:"existence of multi - party system",c:"prevalence of corrupt practices",d:"persistent rural - urban migration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:408,question:"Which of the following is not a function of the National Drug Law Enforcement Agency (NDLEA)?",option:{a:"Applying and implementing all drug laws",b:"Arresting, investigating and prosecuting drug traffickers",c:"Undertaking the registration of companies dealing 	in drugs",d:"Carrying out enlightenment campaigns on drug trafficking"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:380,question:"In spite of the state of affairs reflected in the above monologue, the citizens can make the country better by being committed to",option:{a:"promoting inter-communal relations",b:"strengthening capacity building",c:"championing moral values",d:"encouraging interpersonal relations"},section:"Oh Motherland, you were a precious country, a beacon of hope and aspiration as well as toga of pride of your citizens at independence. However, today you are bedeviled with evil, engulfed in darkness and to say the obvious, at the edge of total moral collapse. Corruption, fraud, deception and dishonesty are prevalent; drug peddlers are having a field day. In schools and colleges, radicalism, prostitution, cultism, examination malpractice among other social vices are order of the day.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:294,question:"Public service belongs to ................",option:{a:"the legislative arm of government",b:"the judiciary arm of government",c:"senate arm of government",d:"the executive arm of government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:407,question:"Cultism in tertiary institutions in Nigeria was originally introduced to",option:{a:"perpetuate the use of local gin and alcohol",b:"harass opponents of university administrators",c:"fight colonialism and oppressive rules",d:"promote inter-communal marriages."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:181,question:"Public Corporations are financed",option:{a:"by tax payers",b:"with private funds",c:"with entrepreneurial funds",d:"by political parties"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:252,question:"Ejiro, who is not sick decide to take the same drug for the same duration as recommended for Omonigho by the doctor.Ejiro’s action can be described as a form of",option:{a:"preventive measure",b:"drug abuse",c:"drug trafficking",d:"Self help activity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:20,question:"According to the story, Imoh’s parents were",option:{a:"wealthy couple",b:"prominent politicians",c:"honest and responsible",d:"religious fanatics"},section:"Imoh lived with her parents in Kakuri. They were good citizens who detested all forms of immoral acts. Both at home and in school, Imoh had been taught the virtues and values of a good citizen. However, while in a bus on her way home from school, the conductor forgot to ask for her fare. She knew that the right thing to do was to pay even when the conductor had forgotten to collect the fare. She also knew that there were other things she could do with the money if it was not paid, but she did what was expected by informing the conductor and paying the fare.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:52,question:"The following are values that promote interpersonal relationship, except",option:{a:"caring.",b:"honesty.",c:"patience",d:"properties."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:198,question:"The primary duty of the police force is to",option:{a:"Make law",b:"Interpret the law",c:"Deal with danfo and okada drivers",d:"Non of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:146,question:"Political values are acquired in any given society through",option:{a:"Political re-orientation",b:"Political campaign",c:"Political socialization",d:"Political indoctrination"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:27,question:"Which of the following is not necessary for public servants to perform effectively?",option:{a:"In - service training",b:"Appointment based on nepotism",c:"Value re - orientation for public servants",d:"Incentives for meeting set goals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:347,question:"The Fourth Schedule of the 1999 Constitution of Nigeria outlines the functions of",option:{a:"federal government",b:"local government",c:"national government",d:"state government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:62,question:"Franchise means right to",option:{a:"contest for political post",b:"join association",c:"live in Nigeria",d:"vote and be voted for"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:236,question:"The lack of interest in politics and political activities by the citizens of a country is known as",option:{a:"political disinterestedness",b:"political culture",c:"political disintegration",d:"political apathy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:159,question:"Citizenship is acquired by an alien through",option:{a:"registration",b:"birth",c:"Conferment",d:"Naturalization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:38,question:"From Ada’s admonition, it could be deduced that taking hard drugs could",option:{a:"make people respect the addicts.",b:"lead to insanity of the addicts",c:"make people to adore the drug addicts",d:"ensure courteous behaviour by the addicts"},section:"Ada:      Wanja, where are you going to in this ungodly hour of the night? <br> 	Wanja:   I am heading towards my usual joint to enjoy myself <br>	 	Ada:       Which joint?<br> 	Wanja:   XYZ. Night Club, where I take marijuana and alcoholic beverages. I really want to be high 			      tonight so that when people see me tomorrow, they will fear and respect me.<br> 	Ada:     Remember, people who work under the influence of hard drugs and alcoholic beverages are prone to either psychiatric problems or premature death. Softly young man, imbibe good - natured character, you have the world at your feet and a destiny to fulfil. Pray you will not be the architect of your own misfortune.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:157,question:"Membership of a society is",option:{a:"conventional",b:"Mandatory",c:"Voluntary",d:"Constitutional"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:53,question:"The responsibilities of government to   its citizens include the following, except",option:{a:"creating employment opportunity",b:"maintenance of law and order",c:"payment of property tax to its citizens",d:"protection of lives and property"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:220,question:"The farthest government to the people is the ............ government",option:{a:"Local",b:"State",c:"Federal",d:"A and B above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:145,question:"The former NAFDAC DG Prof Dora Akunyili died on",option:{a:"June 9. 2014",b:"June 17, 2014",c:"June 7, 2014",d:"May 27, 2014"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:51,question:"A representative of a commonwealth country in another member state is known as a / an.",option:{a:"ambassador",b:"attaché.",c:"consul-general.",d:"high commissioner."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:137,question:"When a group of people believe in and keep to certain norms, values and ways of life of their community since its creation, we call this .................",option:{a:"religion",b:"stereotypes",c:"traditions",d:"custom"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:169,question:"The term V. I. O. mean",option:{a:"Vehicle inspection officer",b:"vehicle implementation officer",c:"vehicle induce operation",d:"vehicle induction officer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:72,question:"What does “35% affirmative action” of the present administration stand for? More",option:{a:"PDP  stalwarts   should   be engaged in government",b:"political positions for women in government",c:"women to be considered for campaign",d:"women to be elected as governors"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:300,question:"Which of the following are Ebola Emergency lines",option:{a:"08023169484 or 08033086660",b:"08023361936 or 08034623521",c:"08023164216 or 08033065936",d:"08055281400 or 08023361936"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:428,question:"Which of the following is a major challenge to civil society in Nigeria?",option:{a:"Value disorientation",b:"Diverse political interests",c:"Inadequate funding",d:"Unstable political system"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:422,question:"A bill passed by the National Assembly requires the assent of the president before it becomes law. The law can be declared null and void by the court of law. The process above emphasizes the",option:{a:"supremacy of judiciary over other arms of government",b:"relationship among the arms of government",c:"importance of law makers in a democracy",d:"fundamentals of the rule of law."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:371,question:"Preventive measures of HIV/AIDS do not include",option:{a:"abstinence",b:"screening of blood before transfusion",c:"use of barrier method",d:"stigmatization of victims"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:308,question:"The number of Girls abducted by members of Boko Haram at Chibok in 2014 is roughly",option:{a:"200",b:"219",c:"419",d:"180"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:409,question:"An individual who finds it difficult to control in-take of drug is known as drug",option:{a:"baron",b:"traffickers",c:"mogul",d:"addict"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:42,question:"The quotation above shows that the speaker is concerned about",option:{a:"nationalism",b:"revolution",c:"tourism",d:"welfarism"},section:"“Here is your country. Cherish these natural wonders, cherish the natural resources, cherish the history and romance as sacred heritage, for your children and your children’s children. Do not let selfish men or greedy interests skin your country of its beauty, its riches...”",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:416,question:"HIV/AIDS is generally described as terminal in nature because it is",option:{a:"preventable",b:"transmittable",c:"avertable",d:"incurable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:107,question:"The following are duties to be performed by the citizens of a country EXCEPT",option:{a:"Destroying government properties",b:"obey law and order",c:"payment of tax",d:"show loyalty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:147,question:"To ensure the rights and freedom of citizens; the power of the arms of government must be",option:{a:"fused",b:"incorporated",c:"separated",d:"rotated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:178,question:"All type of government perform all the following functions except",option:{a:"providing welfare and developmental facilities",b:"maintaining law and order",c:"encouraging the struggle for power",d:"encouraging trade with other state"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:149,question:"The commission charged with the conduct of federal 	elections in Nigeria between 2014 and 2015 is..........",option:{a:"Nec",b:"fedeco",c:"Inec",d:"Necon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:67,question:"The right of an individual to seek redress in a law court is categorized under",option:{a:"economic.",b:"political",c:"procedural,",d:"social"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:318,question:"Which of the following was a former military head of state in Nigeria",option:{a:"MKO Abiola",b:"Goodluck Jonathan",c:"General Idiagbon",d:"General Babagida"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:230,question:"What is the minimum age for voters in Nigeria",option:{a:"15",b:"20",c:"18",d:"50"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:342,question:"The former PHCN is a good example of .................. in Nigeria",option:{a:"civil service",b:"perfect competition",c:"public corporation",d:"private monopoly"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:281,question:"Juvenile delinquency refers to",option:{a:"active youths participation in sports",b:"wrong doings by the youths",c:"Refusal to worship God by the youths",d:"Urban Rural migration by the youth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:243,question:"An organization whose ultimate aim is to gain the control of government and implement its programmes is known as a",option:{a:"Trade Union",b:"Local Government",c:"Political Party",d:"Pressure Group"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:143,question:"Motorcyclists must always protect their heads with safety ............. which must be properly fastened",option:{a:"seat belt",b:"head guild",c:"helmets",d:"cap cycles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:13,question:"The National Assembly, Presidency and Court which are inter - related and interdependent in our democracy constitute the",option:{a:"tiers of government",b:"types of democracy",c:"forms of government.",d:"arms of government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:433,question:"Which of the following is necessary for the effective application of the rule of law?",option:{a:"Political will to ensure that laws are obeyed",b:"Employment opportunities for all citizens",c:"The fusion of the three arms of government",d:"Extension of the retirement age of judges"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:283,question:"Consumers of ......... especially ........... and ..............stand the a great risk of contacting the Ebola disease",option:{a:"fish, tilapia, titus",b:"bush meat, monkey, bat",c:"meat, cow, dog",d:"vegetable, water leaf, bitter leaf"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:204,question:"One of the ways to prevent the spread of HIV/AIDs is",option:{a:"Not to eat in fast food joints",b:"Not to shake hands with anybody",c:"To avoid any object contaminated with blood",d:"Sleep under a mosquito net"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:200,question:"Which of the following is NOT an offence",option:{a:"Tax avoidance",b:"Tax evidence",c:"Stealing by trick",d:"Money laundering"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:87,question:"One of the following is a country as well as a continent.",option:{a:"Africa",b:"Antarctica",c:"Asia",d:"Australia"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:123,question:"The clause which exempts the president from being prosecuted while still in office is called",option:{a:"military clause",b:"special clause",c:"conviction clause",d:"immunity clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:258,question:"In the year 2014, the Nigerian President Good luck Ebelle Jonathan  urged Nigerians to .......... the rumors  that drinking and bathing with salt water prevents or cures Ebola virus",option:{a:"ignore",b:"accept",c:"welcome",d:"embrace"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:192,question:"Colonization of Africa was mainly motivated by",option:{a:"security consideration",b:"economic reasons",c:"religious reasons",d:"cultural factor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:91,question:"The headquarters of ECOWAS is located in",option:{a:"Abuja",b:"Accra",c:"Adis-Ababa",d:"Lome"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:229,question:"The individual rights would be better protected if enshrined in the ..................",option:{a:"Courts",b:"Constitutions",c:"Bible and Quran",d:"National Newspapers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:98,question:"What arm of the criminal justice system is prison?",option:{a:"first",b:"second",c:"third",d:"none"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:359,question:"The effect of human trafficking on the victims is",option:{a:"illiteracy",b:"affluence",c:"exposure",d:"exploitation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:227,question:"The system of government in which all aspects of life are controlled by the government is",option:{a:"democracy",b:"totalitarianism",c:"capitalism",d:"socialism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:136,question:"The process whereby an individual choose to favour a person who come from his family or tribe over other people or tribes is known as",option:{a:"stereotype",b:"ethnicity",c:"nepotism",d:"favouritism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:110,question:"The act of counting the numbers of people living in a country in order to determine the total numbers of 	people in a state is known as .......",option:{a:"election",b:"national population census",c:"voting",d:"rights"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:111,question:"The last population census in Nigeria was conducted in ...........",option:{a:"2003",b:"2006",c:"2007",d:"2005"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:413,question:"The responsibility of empowering the youth rests mostly with",option:{a:"the political class",b:"religious organizations",c:"university administrators",d:"national government"},section:"One major trend in Kantoga Republic today, especially during elections, is the engagement of youths by some politicians for political thuggery, rigging, stuffing of ballot boxes and other related electoral offences. Most of the youths who are engaged in these crimes have no means of livelihood or are school drop-outs. These youths are Kantoguans who ought to benefit from the enormous wealth and resources of the nation.<br><br>  Unfortunately, this is not the case at the moment. Indeed, it is the duty of government , especially at the centre, to provide entrepreneurial skill acquisition program and start-up funds for small scale businesses to empower the youths. This will reduce the chances of engagement of youths for wrong purposes.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:261,question:"On a particular day in 2014, the National flag was flown half mask. This act symbolizes",option:{a:"National tailors day",b:"National mourning",c:"Children’s day",d:"Golden jubilee celebration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:255,question:"As a citizen you can be deprived of your Fundamental Human Rights during",option:{a:"Emergency Rule",b:"Election period",c:"National day celebration",d:"National public holidays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:259,question:"The primary duty of the army is to",option:{a:"execute the law",b:"interpret the law",c:"overthrow the government when there is anarchy",d:"defend the country against external aggression"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:337,question:"Some years to come, when you become the President of Nigeria, which of the options below will you choose 	to eradicate porzverty in the country",option:{a:"carry all the poor people away from Nigeria to another country so when there are no poor people poverty will be gone forever",b:"print plenty Naira Notes and give millions to every Nigeria",c:"Import plenty Agricultural and Manufactured goods",d:"None of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:85,question:"Nigeria is now hundred years since amalgamation which means she has celebrated — anniversary.",option:{a:"amalgamation.",b:"centenary.",c:"golden jubilee.",d:"independence."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:19,question:"Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) is based on the resolution of the",option:{a:"Human Rights Watch",b:"United Nations Organization",c:"Amnesty International",d:"League of Nations."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:172,question:"A constitution that is very easy to amend is called a ...... constitution",option:{a:"rigid",b:"flexible",c:"an easy",d:"simple"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:381,question:"Based on the monologue above, the best approach to curb moral decadence in the motherland is by",option:{a:"value re-orientation",b:"introducing war against corruption",c:"legalizing capital punishment",d:"sending corrupt officials on exile"},section:"Oh Motherland, you were a precious country, a beacon of hope and aspiration as well as toga of pride of your citizens at independence. However, today you are bedeviled with evil, engulfed in darkness and to say the obvious, at the edge of total moral collapse. Corruption, fraud, deception and dishonesty are prevalent; drug peddlers are having a field day. In schools and colleges, radicalism, prostitution, cultism, examination malpractice among other social vices are order of the day.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:305,question:"A sense of right and wrong guiding a person’s action is known as",option:{a:"attitude",b:"conscience",c:"action",d:"manner"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:286,question:"The Ebola disease is usually acquired when a person comes in contact with",option:{a:"the blood or bodily fluids of an infested organism",b:"anybody whose name is Bola",c:"any animal",d:"snake fish"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:92,question:"Human rights abuse can be prevented through the following, except",option:{a:"constitutional means",b:"court of law",c:"mass literacy",d:"protest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:365,question:"Drug law enforcement agencies in Nigeria are not empowered to",option:{a:"execute drug suspects",b:"arrest drug barons",c:"prosecute drug traffickers",d:"rehabilitate drug addicts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:269,question:"Human traffickers usually engage their victims .........",option:{a:"in educative programs",b:"in forced labour",c:"in skill acquisition activities",d:"in recreational activities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:285,question:"The judicial organs of government is the body which",option:{a:"makes the law",b:"implements the law",c:"interpreters the law",d:"rewards lawmakers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:48,question:"The upper legislative chamber of the National Assembly of Nigeria is also known as the",option:{a:"honourables",b:"house of commons.",c:"house of lords",d:"senate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:28,question:"One of the conditions which can limit the enjoyment of Human Rights in Nigeria is the",option:{a:"acceptance of foreign aid by the government",b:"improvement in literacy level of the citizens",c:"declaration of state of emergency by government",d:"periodic review of the constitution by government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:419,question:"The above quotation summarizes the",option:{a:"Universal Declaration of Human Rights.",b:"African Charter on Human Rights.",c:"Geneva Conventions and Protocols.",d:"United Nations Organization Charter."},section:"“All human beings are born free and equal in dignity and rights. They are endowed with reason and 		conscience and should act towards one another in a spirit of brotherhood”.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:254,question:"The Ebola virus sneaked into Nigeria through",option:{a:"The Liberian born American, Mr Patrick Sawyer",b:"The Ghanaian born American, Mr Patrick Sayer",c:"Members of the Boko Haram",d:"Monkeys and bats"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:231,question:"Which of these characteristics of the civil service ensure continuity of government?",option:{a:"Neutrality",b:"Permanence",c:"Bureaucracy",d:"Loyalty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:393,question:"Which of the following factors does not affect interpersonal relationship?",option:{a:"Communication",b:"Withdrawal",c:"Compatibility",d:"Forgiveness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:257,question:"Plenty of money in the society, not backed by commensurate productive activities can lead to",option:{a:"deflation",b:"inflation",c:"National developmental",d:"cashless society"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:251,question:"If Omonigho had taken the tablet one three times a day for six days his action constitutes a kind of",option:{a:"good drug administration",b:"drug abuse",c:"drug trafficking",d:"none of the abuse"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:412,question:"From the above write-up what category of Kantoguan youth deserves to be effectively empowered?",option:{a:"Children of the ruling political class",b:"Unemployed youths and school drop-outs",c:"University undergraduates",d:"Youth wing of religious organizations"},section:"One major trend in Kantoga Republic today, especially during elections, is the engagement of youths by some politicians for political thuggery, rigging, stuffing of ballot boxes and other related electoral offences. Most of the youths who are engaged in these crimes have no means of livelihood or are school drop-outs. These youths are Kantoguans who ought to benefit from the enormous wealth and resources of the nation.<br><br>  Unfortunately, this is not the case at the moment. Indeed, it is the duty of government , especially at the centre, to provide entrepreneurial skill acquisition program and start-up funds for small scale businesses to empower the youths. This will reduce the chances of engagement of youths for wrong purposes.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:392,question:"Two forms of road signs are regulatory and",option:{a:"punitive",b:"informative",c:"persuasive",d:"inhibitive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:i};export{i as data,n as default,e as message,a as status,o as subject,t as total};
